<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-09-19T03:58:44+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Linda Joe Thadeus</title><subtitle>A personal website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Can we the reasoning AI model for DSA Practice ?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/dsa-training-ai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can we the reasoning AI model for DSA Practice ?"/><published>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/dsa-training-ai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/dsa-training-ai/"><![CDATA[<p>The openAI has released a reasoning AI that can solve Marhematical problems. I asked it to count the no. of Rs in the strawberry and it responded correctly. People also say that it is solving JEE questions.</p> <p>That’s amazing.</p> <p>Let’s try to use this AI as our tutor for finally learning DSA Fundamentals.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="dsa"/><category term="dsa,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="software"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The openAI has released a reasoning AI that can solve Marhematical problems. I asked it to count the no. of Rs in the strawberry and it responded correctly. People also say that it is solving JEE questions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I transitioned from surviving to living?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/surviving-living-orig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I transitioned from surviving to living?"/><published>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/surviving-living-orig</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/surviving-living-orig/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="how-i-transitioned-from-surviving-to-living">How I transitioned from surviving to living?</h3> <p>In life and business, direct tools like coercion or force can lead to short-term gains but create long-term harm. What if we could transform these tools into collaborative, value-driven strategies that benefit everyone? For instance, Let us look at “Mugging”. People mug others to get money from others, so that they could make their ends meet. The people who mug others are not happy to do it, the people who get mugged are so unhappy and sometimes get harmed physically too. Let us take another instance, the Indian parents are hitting their kids, why? so that they discipline their children. But, like the previous case, none is happy to do it. So, can we do it in a way that benefits everyone. Sounds Familiar? We are trying to solve this using capitalism’s principles.</p> <p>Let us look at the below steps to do it.</p> <h3 id="1-identify-the-core-objective">1. Identify the Core Objective</h3> <ul> <li>Clarify your goals: Understand the underlying need or desire.</li> <li>Assess motivations: Reflect on why you want to achieve it.</li> </ul> <p>For instance, In the case of Indian Parents hitting their kids, the end-goal of the action is nothing but, disciplining. The thing wrong here is the METHOD used for disciplining the kids.</p> <h3 id="2-understand-the-impact-of-direct-tools">2. Understand the Impact of Direct Tools</h3> <ul> <li>Evaluate consequences: Consider the legal, ethical, and social costs.</li> <li>Acknowledge harm: Recognize how others are negatively affected.</li> </ul> <p>We, millenials have ourselves faced the harmful effects of hitting kids. The direct con is the child resenting the parent and the sibling for not helping them. The indirect con is the sibling resenting both themselves for not helping their sibling and the parent for the emotional hurt for making them witness the punishment.</p> <h3 id="3-reframe-the-objective-into-a-value-proposition">3. Reframe the Objective into a Value Proposition</h3> <ul> <li>Shift perspective: How can you achieve your goal while adding value?</li> <li>Identify mutual benefits: Find what others need and how you can help.</li> </ul> <p>Now, all we need to do is the change the METHOD deployed in the situation to achieve the goal. Let us take an example from my childhood when I was thrashed. I was not thrashed much by parents when compared to my sibling. I only have data only for my case, so let us focus on that. When I got thrashed, it was because I was overplaying with my neighbours that I was causing trouble to my neighbours. So, instead of my mom (She had only hit me once, the major punishments were conducted by my dad on my sibling - twin) hitting me, she could have hit me and added some LOVE component to it, which she did, I loved my Mom. Let us take another scenario, where I was punished by my Head Mistress for not tying my hair properly. She punished me for a long time that would have worked simple cases, but for me it would not because, I had a stressful home. Instead, she should have UNDERSTOOD (EMPATHY) my problems and informed by parents. So, eventually, after some time, she informed my Mom and my mom tied my hair properly. So, that is how, it has to be done.</p> <h3 id="4-develop-a-mutually-beneficial-strategy">4. Develop a Mutually Beneficial Strategy</h3> <ul> <li>Innovate solutions: Meet your goals through products or services people want.</li> <li>Leverage skills: Use your talents and resources to provide value.</li> </ul> <p>In the story of me getting punished by my HM (Head Mistress), I was eventually understood, by them contacting my Mom. But, it was sorta late. Because, this was a missed opportunity to capitalise on the problem early on. They could have informed my mom early on and thereby making me a bit less resentful of them and they might have had an ALUMNA, who would be GLAD to reach out to them for the future endeavours. But, they had a lot of people, and I am no longer hateful of them because of time and I am UNDERSTANDING their pains too. I still don’t want to collaborate with them ever, because of the way, they ill-treated my SICK Mom.</p> <h3 id="5-establish-ethical-and-transparent-practices">5. Establish Ethical and Transparent Practices</h3> <ul> <li>Set clear guidelines: Ensure legal and ethical methods.</li> <li>Promote fairness: Build trust through equitable actions.</li> </ul> <p>Anyway, we could have avoided this DRAMA, if we had just followed a set of rules for taking care of students with issues. Like, if I am opening a school, and I see a child not taking care of themselves, even when I had pointed out, I would directly empower them to do it.</p> <p>By following this framework, you transform direct, often harmful tools into ethical strategies that foster collaboration and mutual success, benefiting both you and society.</p> <p><strong>Keywords</strong>: ethical business, collaboration, value-driven strategies, mutual success</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="personal"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How I transitioned from surviving to living?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to transition from surviving to living?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/surviving-living/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to transition from surviving to living?"/><published>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/surviving-living</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/surviving-living/"><![CDATA[<p>In life and business, direct tools like coercion or force can lead to short-term gains but cause long-term harm. What if we could transform these tools into strategies that benefit everyone? Let’s take a familiar example: Indian parents hitting their kids to discipline them. Neither the parent nor the child is happy, and the long-term emotional harm outweighs the short-term behavior correction. The same applies in business—direct force rarely builds lasting success. Instead, we can use <strong>capitalism’s principles</strong> to create value-driven strategies that achieve goals while fostering positive relationships.</p> <h3 id="1-identify-the-core-objective">1. Identify the Core Objective</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Clarify your goals</strong>: Understand the underlying need or desire.</li> <li><strong>Assess motivations</strong>: Reflect on why you want to achieve this.</li> </ul> <p>In the case of parents disciplining their children, the end goal is <strong>discipline</strong>. The issue is <strong>how</strong> that discipline is enforced.</p> <h3 id="2-understand-the-impact-of-direct-tools">2. Understand the Impact of Direct Tools</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Evaluate consequences</strong>: Consider the legal, ethical, and social costs.</li> <li><strong>Acknowledge harm</strong>: Recognize how others are negatively affected.</li> </ul> <p>For example, we Millennials experienced firsthand the harmful effects of physical punishment—resentment toward parents or siblings, and lasting emotional scars.</p> <h3 id="3-reframe-the-objective-into-a-value-proposition">3. Reframe the Objective into a Value Proposition</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Shift perspective</strong>: How can you achieve your goal while adding value?</li> <li><strong>Identify mutual benefits</strong>: Find what others need and how you can help.</li> </ul> <p>As a child, I was once punished by my Head Mistress for not tying my hair properly. If, instead of punishment, she had empathized with my stressful home situation, it could have built understanding and trust. Eventually, my mom resolved the issue, but early empathy would have reduced my resentment.</p> <h3 id="4-develop-a-mutually-beneficial-strategy">4. Develop a Mutually Beneficial Strategy</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Innovate solutions</strong>: Meet your goals through methods that provide value to others.</li> <li><strong>Leverage skills</strong>: Use your talents and resources to benefit everyone.</li> </ul> <p>My school missed an opportunity to <strong>collaborate</strong> with my family early on, which could have prevented emotional harm. Timely action can strengthen relationships, turning a punitive moment into a <strong>bonding opportunity</strong>.</p> <h3 id="5-establish-ethical-and-transparent-practices">5. Establish Ethical and Transparent Practices</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Set clear guidelines</strong>: Ensure legal and ethical methods.</li> <li><strong>Promote fairness</strong>: Build trust through equitable actions.</li> </ul> <p>By following this framework, you transform direct, often harmful tools into ethical strategies that foster collaboration and mutual success, benefiting both you and society.</p> <p><strong>Keywords</strong>: ethical business, collaboration, value-driven strategies, mutual success</p> <hr/> <p>What do you think? Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="graceful-bonding"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="graceful-bonding"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In life and business, direct tools like coercion or force can lead to short-term gains but cause long-term harm. What if we could transform these tools into strategies that benefit everyone? Let’s take a familiar example: Indian parents hitting their kids to discipline them. Neither the parent nor the child is happy, and the long-term emotional harm outweighs the short-term behavior correction. The same applies in business—direct force rarely builds lasting success. Instead, we can use capitalism’s principles to create value-driven strategies that achieve goals while fostering positive relationships.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to navigate the trust less world?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/trustless-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to navigate the trust less world?"/><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/trustless-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/trustless-world/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="we-live-in-a-jealous-society">We live in a jealous society?</h2> <p>Our trust on others has never been this low, based on my observation. I remember the days, when we didn’t have smartphones, social media, but, the neighbours were not really too jealous of us and we were not too jealous of them either. We were not too much richer or too much poorer than our neighbours. We were not all working in the same domain, like my parents were both bureaucrats and our neighbours were once bureaucrat and a home maker, another time they were engineers, and some other time they were teachers. Of course, people made varied amounts of money, a little bit jealousy was there, but nothing of the current scale.</p> <h2 id="we-live-in-a-competitive-society">We live in a competitive society?</h2> <p>We are all living in competition with others all of the times. I remember the days when we did not have this much rigorous competition when our neighbour had a reward.</p> <h2 id="we-live-in-a-trust-less-society">We live in a trust less society?</h2> <p>We do not trust our neighbours anymore. TBH I stopped trusting my dad or sister even. There’s no love for others anymore. Of course, I have my reasons.</p> <h2 id="does-abundance-creates-isolation">Does Abundance creates Isolation?</h2> <p>Abundance creates isolation, trust less ness, independence. I read an article about Meadow voles and prairies voles, and their relationships and lifestyles based on their environment. Basically it said that the voles that were in Meadows were sexually promiscuous while their prairies counterparts weren’t. In Meadows, where they would find plenty of food, the voles didn’t care about their relationships, their younger ones, but in prairies, the voles had to gather food and seek food and food wasn’t abundant but scarce, so the male voles were monogamous and even helped the female voles to raise their offsprings, and it was a necessity that they remain monogamous for the survival of their offsprings unlike the meadows voles, where even young voles could easily afford to find food themselves easily. Also, the meadow voles were not very close with each other or socially bonding a lot as much as their prairies counterparts.</p> <p>So, abundance removes the necessity of support from the others, scarcity connects people together on the basis of needs.</p> <p>As world moves forward we will be only abundant in all areas making us all independent of each other and totally trust less. And when there is jealousy and other negative traits then average people lose their trustworthiness.</p> <h2 id="how-to-navigate-a-trust-less-society">How to navigate a trust less society?</h2> <p>We need to use the principles of blockchain technology here. The blockchain technology is used for transacting without a central trust system. They use a special network where each node has to verify their identity, keep track of transactions and then commit their transactions or contracts. Same way, we could also, verify ourselves, keep track of our commitments and other’s commitments and then enforce our legal agreements to the other person.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="words,"/><category term="general"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We live in a jealous society?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What happened to me - childhood?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-hard-childhood/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What happened to me - childhood?"/><published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-hard-childhood</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-hard-childhood/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="what-happened-my-pathetic-childhood">What happened?: My Pathetic Childhood</h3> <p>Growing up, I faced significant emotional challenges that deeply affected my self-esteem. My skin problems, emotional stress at home, and feelings of guilt weighed on me for years. But there came a turning point, and this is how I began to overcome it.</p> <h3 id="dependence-and-emotional-boundaries">Dependence and Emotional Boundaries</h3> <p>As a teenager, I relied heavily on my sick mother—not just for support, but to shamelessly hide my despicable self from the world. I was pathetically dependent on my sick mom. I had low self-esteem, worsened by family stress and my insecurities about my skin. <strong>“I wasn’t emotionally secure, and I used my sick mom to hide me from the cruel world, which left me feeling guilty.”</strong></p> <h3 id="guilt-and-trespassing">Guilt and Trespassing</h3> <p>I carried immense guilt. <strong>“I felt guilty for using my mom, was punished unnecessarily for others’ mistakes, and trespassed upon by those around me.”</strong> Lacking boundaries, It wasn’t until I left home that I finally found relief.</p> <h3 id="finding-freedom-and-anonymity">Finding Freedom and Anonymity</h3> <p><strong>“One day, I left that place for a better life.”</strong> The emotional weight lifted when I went away to school. <strong>“Being a student protected me by providing anonymity.”</strong> This new environment, away from the constant stress, allowed me to heal. I was able to focus on myself without being overwhelmed.</p> <h3 id="lessons-in-boundaries-and-self-worth">Lessons in Boundaries and Self-Worth</h3> <p>Looking back, I see how important emotional distance was in rebuilding my self-esteem. Setting boundaries was key to finding balance. Emotional freedom is about recognizing when to step away from toxic environments and reclaiming control over your life.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="key-issues">Key Issues:</h3> <ol> <li>Pathetic dependence on my sick mom</li> <li>I wasn’t emotionally secure, and I used my sick mom to hide from the cruel world, which left me feeling guilty</li> <li>I felt guilty for using my mom, punished for others’ mistakes, and trespassed upon by those around me</li> <li>One day, I left that place for a better life</li> <li>Being in a similar crowd gave me invisibility</li> </ol> <hr/> <h3 id="key-factors-that-helped">Key factors that helped</h3> <ol> <li>Routine and stability</li> <li>Physical activity</li> <li>Reduced visibility by joining a similar crowd</li> <li>Emotional distance from triggers</li> </ol> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="personal"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What happened?: My Pathetic Childhood]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to run LLM on a laptop?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/llm-1-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to run LLM on a laptop?"/><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/llm-1-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/llm-1-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="how-to-run-a-llm-in-a-laptop">How to run a LLM in a laptop?</h3> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Get</span> <span class="n">a</span> <span class="n">laptop</span> <span class="k">with</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mi">16</span> <span class="n">GB</span> <span class="n">RAM</span> <span class="ow">and</span> <span class="n">core</span> <span class="n">i7</span> <span class="nf">processor </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">GPU</span> <span class="n">too</span> <span class="ow">is</span> <span class="n">good</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">but</span> <span class="n">I</span> <span class="n">did</span> <span class="ow">not</span> <span class="n">use</span> <span class="n">it</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">It</span> <span class="n">took</span> <span class="mi">800</span><span class="o">%</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="n">cpu</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">10</span><span class="o">%</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="n">Memory</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="n">GB</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">a</span> <span class="n">HelloWorld</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Get</span> <span class="n">Permission</span> <span class="n">to</span> <span class="n">LLAMA</span> <span class="n">LLM</span> <span class="n">usage</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="nf">meta </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Waiting</span> <span class="n">Time</span> <span class="mi">24</span> <span class="o">-</span> <span class="mi">48</span> <span class="n">Hours</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">frankly</span> <span class="n">unnecessary</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Install</span> <span class="n">HuggingFace</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">hub</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Download</span> <span class="nb">any</span> <span class="n">LLAMA</span> <span class="n">model</span> <span class="n">variant</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="n">HF</span> <span class="n">using</span> <span class="n">huggingface</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nf">cli </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">7</span><span class="n">B</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Install</span> <span class="n">ctransformers</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">6</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Run</span> <span class="n">the</span> <span class="nf">script </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">that</span> <span class="n">you</span> <span class="n">create</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="n">that</span> <span class="n">opens</span> <span class="n">the</span> <span class="n">downloaded</span> <span class="n">LLM</span> <span class="nb">file</span> <span class="ow">and</span> <span class="n">use</span> <span class="n">prompts</span> <span class="n">on</span> <span class="nf">it </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Check</span> <span class="nb">any</span> <span class="n">HF</span> <span class="n">LLAMA</span> <span class="n">model</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">this</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></figure> <h3 id="did-it-work-for-you">Did it work for you?</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="llm"/><category term="world,"/><category term="linux"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to run a LLM in a laptop?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Words Are Not Enough?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-not-inclusive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Words Are Not Enough?"/><published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-not-inclusive</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-not-inclusive/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="why-should-we-not-take-words-as-the-primary-mode-of-communication">Why Should We Not Take Words as the Primary Mode of Communication?</h3> <p>I have started to dislike using words as our primary mode of communication because:</p> <ol> <li>Firstly, not a lot of well-intentioned words are being spoken.</li> <li>Even if they are spoken with good intention, the choice of words, if not pleasing to hear, could mess up the receiver and sender relationships.</li> <li>The words need to be learned, so they can be exploited by people with more practice. Older people have an edge over younger ones, and newborns totally can’t use them, so it’s not really a fair field.</li> <li>Words are not inclusive of animals, plants, and other co-living beings.</li> <li>Narcissists are despicable.</li> </ol> <p>Now, what communication does a newborn understand? I think it’s action, physical touch, facial expressions, and emotions. Even other animals can understand physical touch, facial expressions, and emotions. So, why don’t we just use these more often?</p> <p>In fact, Priscilla Dunstan, an expert in baby language, discovered a few sounds used by babies under 3 months old and helped us to include their “vocabulary” in our words.</p> <p>Also, if we want to reduce communication with strangers, we can physically reduce the distance and use actions alongside words.</p> <h3 id="so-isnt-it-better-to-reduce-words-and-use-other-sensory-inputs-like-facial-expressions-and-body-language-along-with-words">So, Isn’t It Better to Reduce Words and Use Other Sensory Inputs Like Facial Expressions and Body Language Along with Words?</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="words,"/><category term="one"/><category term="minute"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why Should We Not Take Words as the Primary Mode of Communication?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Brain Management is the WORST</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/second-brain-emotional-issues-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Brain Management is the WORST"/><published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/second-brain-emotional-issues-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/second-brain-emotional-issues-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="storm-of-negative-thoughts-again">Storm of Negative Thoughts again.</h3> <p>Recently, I posted about the reason for having a storm of negative thoughts and again I got a storm. And, this time too my stomach was not at ease. I had eaten too much peanut butter that day, from the morning till the night, we Indians are not careful with the quantity.</p> <p>This time, I couldn’t even sleep well as I was having racing heart and I started getting the negative thoughts. After a while, I slept, but I was not fully rested and that shows that we all have to be careful with out food.</p> <p>That also implies that, our emotions are mainly from our stomach? stomach bacteria?</p> <h3 id="guess-we-should-really-be-cautious-about-what-we-eat">Guess, we should really be cautious about what we eat.</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="health"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Storm of Negative Thoughts again. Recently, I posted about the reason for having a storm of negative thoughts and again I got a storm. And, this time too my stomach was not at ease. I had eaten too much peanut butter that day, from the morning till the night, we Indians are not careful with the quantity.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who are Responsible for an Abuse?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/actors-in-abuse-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who are Responsible for an Abuse?"/><published>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/actors-in-abuse-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/actors-in-abuse-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="actors-in-an-abuse">Actors in an Abuse</h3> <p>Trauma bonds involve various roles that perpetuate the cycle of abuse:</p> <ol> <li><strong>Victim</strong>: The emotionally or physically harmed individual who feels trapped.</li> <li><strong>Abuser/Perpetrator</strong>: The one who exerts control, often using manipulation and harm.</li> <li><strong>Enabler</strong>: Supports or reinforces the abusive behavior, usually unintentionally.</li> <li><strong>Bystander</strong>: Aware of the abuse but remains passive or uninvolved, they may be empathetic or apathetic</li> <li><strong>Rescuer/Savior</strong>: Tries to help the victim but can inadvertently enable dependency.</li> </ol> <p>These roles, whether active or passive, contribute to the complex dynamics of trauma bonds, making it crucial to recognize and address them for healing.</p> <h3 id="wow-empaths-are-totally-useless-unless-theyre-doing-something-about-their-emotions-right">Wow, empaths are totally useless unless they’re doing something about their emotions, right?</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="words"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actors in an Abuse]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthy Word #1</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-emotional-regulation-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthy Word #1"/><published>2024-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-emotional-regulation-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-emotional-regulation-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="words-emotional-regulation">Words: Emotional Regulation</h3> <p>Recently, I got to know about the word, emotional regulation. I was confused. The capitalist inventors will keep on creating words for selling something I thought. But, it’s really mentioned in multiple trauma related videos and contents.</p> <p>I really wanted to regulate my emotions but I didn’t know how. Then, one day I saw that video on the LinkedIn platform. In that video they said that they would like to think of emotional regulation as “You are hurting but I am not, it’s not my time for the hurt, I am not affected by the event physically so I don’t want to let it affect my emotions.”</p> <h2 id="such-simple-words-na">Such simple words na?</h2> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="words"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Words: Emotional Regulation]]></summary></entry></feed>