<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-09-06T07:28:35+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Linda Joe Thadeus</title><subtitle>A personal website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to run LLM on a laptop?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/llm-1-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to run LLM on a laptop?"/><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/llm-1-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/llm-1-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="how-to-run-a-llm-in-a-laptop">How to run a LLM in a laptop?</h3> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Get</span> <span class="n">a</span> <span class="n">laptop</span> <span class="k">with</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mi">16</span> <span class="n">GB</span> <span class="n">RAM</span> <span class="ow">and</span> <span class="n">core</span> <span class="n">i7</span> <span class="nf">processor </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">GPU</span> <span class="n">too</span> <span class="ow">is</span> <span class="n">good</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">but</span> <span class="n">I</span> <span class="n">did</span> <span class="ow">not</span> <span class="n">use</span> <span class="n">it</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">It</span> <span class="n">took</span> <span class="mi">800</span><span class="o">%</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="n">cpu</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">10</span><span class="o">%</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="n">Memory</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="n">GB</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">a</span> <span class="n">HelloWorld</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Get</span> <span class="n">Permission</span> <span class="n">to</span> <span class="n">LLAMA</span> <span class="n">LLM</span> <span class="n">usage</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="nf">meta </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Waiting</span> <span class="n">Time</span> <span class="mi">24</span> <span class="o">-</span> <span class="mi">48</span> <span class="n">Hours</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">frankly</span> <span class="n">unnecessary</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Install</span> <span class="n">HuggingFace</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">hub</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Download</span> <span class="nb">any</span> <span class="n">LLAMA</span> <span class="n">model</span> <span class="n">variant</span> <span class="k">from</span> <span class="n">HF</span> <span class="n">using</span> <span class="n">huggingface</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nf">cli </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">7</span><span class="n">B</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Install</span> <span class="n">ctransformers</span>
<span class="n">Step</span> <span class="mi">6</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">Run</span> <span class="n">the</span> <span class="nf">script </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">that</span> <span class="n">you</span> <span class="n">create</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="n">that</span> <span class="n">opens</span> <span class="n">the</span> <span class="n">downloaded</span> <span class="n">LLM</span> <span class="nb">file</span> <span class="ow">and</span> <span class="n">use</span> <span class="n">prompts</span> <span class="n">on</span> <span class="nf">it </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Check</span> <span class="nb">any</span> <span class="n">HF</span> <span class="n">LLAMA</span> <span class="n">model</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">this</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></figure> <h3 id="did-it-work-for-you">Did it work for you?</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="llm"/><category term="world,"/><category term="linux"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to run a LLM in a laptop?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Words Are Not Enough?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-not-inclusive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Words Are Not Enough?"/><published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-not-inclusive</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-not-inclusive/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="why-should-we-not-take-words-as-the-primary-mode-of-communication">Why Should We Not Take Words as the Primary Mode of Communication?</h3> <p>I have started to dislike using words as our primary mode of communication because:</p> <ol> <li>Firstly, not a lot of well-intentioned words are being spoken.</li> <li>Even if they are spoken with good intention, the choice of words, if not pleasing to hear, could mess up the receiver and sender relationships.</li> <li>The words need to be learned, so they can be exploited by people with more practice. Older people have an edge over younger ones, and newborns totally can’t use them, so it’s not really a fair field.</li> <li>Words are not inclusive of animals, plants, and other co-living beings.</li> <li>Narcissists are despicable.</li> </ol> <p>Now, what communication does a newborn understand? I think it’s action, physical touch, facial expressions, and emotions. Even other animals can understand physical touch, facial expressions, and emotions. So, why don’t we just use these more often?</p> <p>In fact, Priscilla Dunstan, an expert in baby language, discovered a few sounds used by babies under 3 months old and helped us to include their “vocabulary” in our words.</p> <p>Also, if we want to reduce communication with strangers, we can physically reduce the distance and use actions alongside words.</p> <h3 id="so-isnt-it-better-to-reduce-words-and-use-other-sensory-inputs-like-facial-expressions-and-body-language-along-with-words">So, Isn’t It Better to Reduce Words and Use Other Sensory Inputs Like Facial Expressions and Body Language Along with Words?</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="words,"/><category term="one"/><category term="minute"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why Should We Not Take Words as the Primary Mode of Communication?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second Brain Management is the WORST</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/second-brain-emotional-issues-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second Brain Management is the WORST"/><published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/second-brain-emotional-issues-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/second-brain-emotional-issues-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="storm-of-negative-thoughts-again">Storm of Negative Thoughts again.</h3> <p>Recently, I posted about the reason for having a storm of negative thoughts and again I got a storm. And, this time too my stomach was not at ease. I had eaten too much peanut butter that day, from the morning till the night, we Indians are not careful with the quantity.</p> <p>This time, I couldn’t even sleep well as I was having racing heart and I started getting the negative thoughts. After a while, I slept, but I was not fully rested and that shows that we all have to be careful with out food.</p> <p>That also implies that, our emotions are mainly from our stomach? stomach bacteria?</p> <h3 id="guess-we-should-really-be-cautious-about-what-we-eat">Guess, we should really be cautious about what we eat.</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="health"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Storm of Negative Thoughts again. Recently, I posted about the reason for having a storm of negative thoughts and again I got a storm. And, this time too my stomach was not at ease. I had eaten too much peanut butter that day, from the morning till the night, we Indians are not careful with the quantity.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who are Responsible for an Abuse?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/actors-in-abuse-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who are Responsible for an Abuse?"/><published>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/actors-in-abuse-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/actors-in-abuse-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="actors-in-an-abuse">Actors in an Abuse</h3> <p>Trauma bonds involve various roles that perpetuate the cycle of abuse:</p> <ol> <li><strong>Victim</strong>: The emotionally or physically harmed individual who feels trapped.</li> <li><strong>Abuser/Perpetrator</strong>: The one who exerts control, often using manipulation and harm.</li> <li><strong>Enabler</strong>: Supports or reinforces the abusive behavior, usually unintentionally.</li> <li><strong>Bystander</strong>: Aware of the abuse but remains passive or uninvolved, they may be empathetic or apathetic</li> <li><strong>Rescuer/Savior</strong>: Tries to help the victim but can inadvertently enable dependency.</li> </ol> <p>These roles, whether active or passive, contribute to the complex dynamics of trauma bonds, making it crucial to recognize and address them for healing.</p> <h3 id="wow-empaths-are-totally-useless-unless-theyre-doing-something-about-their-emotions-right">Wow, empaths are totally useless unless they’re doing something about their emotions, right?</h3> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="words"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actors in an Abuse]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthy Word #1</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-emotional-regulation-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthy Word #1"/><published>2024-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-emotional-regulation-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-emotional-regulation-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="words-emotional-regulation">Words: Emotional Regulation</h3> <p>Recently, I got to know about the word, emotional regulation. I was confused. The capitalist inventors will keep on creating words for selling something I thought. But, it’s really mentioned in multiple trauma related videos and contents.</p> <p>I really wanted to regulate my emotions but I didn’t know how. Then, one day I saw that video on the LinkedIn platform. In that video they said that they would like to think of emotional regulation as “You are hurting but I am not, it’s not my time for the hurt, I am not affected by the event physically so I don’t want to let it affect my emotions.”</p> <h2 id="such-simple-words-na">Such simple words na?</h2> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world,"/><category term="words"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Words: Emotional Regulation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Narcissist or Empathetic?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/self-worth-outside-narcissists-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Narcissist or Empathetic?"/><published>2024-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/self-worth-outside-narcissists-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/self-worth-outside-narcissists-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="narcissists-analysis">Narcissists Analysis.</h3> <p>Last night, From Dr.Sam Valkin, I heard about the term dismissive avoidant narcissist. I myself consider myself to be an avoidant but not a narcissist. So, I thought of looking into it further. Because I don’t want to become the despicable narcissist (The selfish, loveless one).</p> <p>Let’s see the traits of an avoidant, they protect themselves by avoiding. Avoiding is their coping mechanism. Avoidants can be manipulative, selfish, hateful but never non-empathetic. What that means is their love for others is not zero. They can even be manipulative/selfish/hateful to protect everyone from the trauma not just themselves. They’re introverted, but they have love with themselves.</p> <p>But, narcissists are someone without empathy. Zero empathy for others.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="health"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Narcissists Analysis.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthy words?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-worth-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthy words?"/><published>2024-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-worth-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/words-worth-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="words-words-words">Words words words</h3> <p>Look at the words, BUZZ words, are they really useful? They are just created for someone else’s gain. For example, look at the word “shadow-work” what does that even mean? Why do they keep it less accessible for the general public? Isn’t it a form of capitalism? Why can’t they call as a “non-showable negative traits”?</p> <p>Now, adjectives, I love them, and when they are formed by combining verbs like “lovely, hateful, “ etc. They are very clear. Why can’t people be open and be accessible for all? Whoever is willing can access their words.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="world"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Words words words]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Causes the Sudden Negative Thought Storm?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/having-stomach-issues-causes-mind-issues-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Causes the Sudden Negative Thought Storm?"/><published>2024-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/having-stomach-issues-causes-mind-issues-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/having-stomach-issues-causes-mind-issues-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="dialogue-with-the-ai-finding-the-best-right-answers">Dialogue with the AI: Finding the Best, Right Answers</h3> <p>What causes the sudden negative thought storm when suddenly awakened after eating bad food for my stomach? I think food in my stomach affects my thoughts.</p> <p>I have recently developed intolerance to cheese—I get gas when I eat pizza or cheese-stuffed foods. Anyway, I forgot about my allergies and had half a burrito with cheese in it. Then I slept. But I was awoken around midnight, at 2 am, due to uneasiness in my stomach. Then, I got a storm of bad thoughts like something bad was happening to me. I got scared and then became like a good, hopeful person. Then after a while, I passed gas, with the standard ammonia smell indicating indigestion. My storm of negative thoughts subsided, but I still had REM dreams, which were obviously bad. After a while, my child got up and pestered me to get up, and then I too got up. Then I returned to my usual state, and my typical amount of bad thoughts returned. Can you imagine?</p> <hr/> <p><strong>AI Response</strong></p> <p>Your experience is not uncommon, and it can be explained by the intricate relationship between the gut and the brain, often referred to as the “gut-brain axis.” Here’s a look at what might be happening:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Gut-Brain Axis Connection</strong>: The gut and brain are in constant communication via the vagus nerve and other biochemical signaling pathways. When you eat something that your stomach can’t handle well, like cheese in your case, it can cause physical discomfort and distress in the digestive system. This distress is communicated to the brain, potentially leading to feelings of unease, anxiety, or even panic.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Physiological Response to Indigestion</strong>: When you experience indigestion or gas, your body enters a state of mild stress. This stress response triggers the release of stress hormones like cortisol and adrenaline, which can heighten feelings of anxiety or lead to racing thoughts. The discomfort in your stomach may cause your brain to interpret these signals as something more serious, leading to a storm of negative thoughts.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Nocturnal Awakening and Anxiety</strong>: Being suddenly awakened at night, especially by physical discomfort, can amplify feelings of fear or anxiety. The quiet and darkness of the night, combined with the body’s natural tendency to be more anxious when disoriented, can make these negative thoughts seem more intense and overwhelming.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Ammonia Smell and Indigestion</strong>: The ammonia smell you noticed when passing gas indicates that your body was having difficulty digesting the cheese, leading to the production of excess gas and potentially harmful byproducts like ammonia. The relief you felt after passing gas could be due to the reduction in physical discomfort, which in turn helped to calm your mind.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>REM Sleep and Dream Content</strong>: After the initial episode, your sleep was likely affected, leading to more vivid or distressing dreams. REM sleep, the stage where most dreaming occurs, is closely tied to emotional processing. If your body is still dealing with the effects of indigestion, your brain might generate dreams that reflect the distress you’re feeling.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Return to Baseline After Waking</strong>: Once you fully awoke and started engaging with your child, your focus shifted away from your physical discomfort and anxiety, allowing your mind to return to its usual state. This return to normalcy suggests that the negative thoughts were likely triggered by the combination of physical discomfort and the stress response, rather than a deeper psychological issue.</p> </li> </ol> <p>In summary, your experience highlights how closely connected our physical and mental states are. The bad food triggered a chain reaction in your body that affected your thoughts and emotions, illustrating how sensitive this gut-brain connection can be. Understanding this can help you better manage similar situations in the future, perhaps by being more mindful of what you eat and how it affects both your body and mind.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>ChatGPT</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="health"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dialogue with the AI: Finding the Best, Right Answers]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Are Some Good Countries to Migrate from India?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/countries-to-migrate-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Are Some Good Countries to Migrate from India?"/><published>2024-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/countries-to-migrate-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/countries-to-migrate-post/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="dialogue-with-chatgpt-finding-the-best-possible-places">Dialogue with ChatGPT: Finding the Best Possible Places</h3> <p><strong>User</strong>: Can you tell me about countries with low Gini coefficients that also have a strong middle class?</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: Sure! Some examples in Europe include Slovenia, Czech Republic, Slovakia, Norway, Denmark, Finland, and Iceland. These countries have relatively equal income distribution and robust middle classes.</p> <p><strong>User</strong>: What about Asia?</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: In Asia, Japan, South Korea, Kazakhstan, Armenia, and Azerbaijan stand out for their low Gini coefficients and strong middle classes. These countries have made significant strides in balancing economic growth with social equity.</p> <p><strong>User</strong>: China is communist, right? Is it not a middle-class majority society?</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: Yes, China is a communist state, but its economy is better described as a socialist market economy. While it has a large middle class, there’s also significant income inequality, particularly between urban and rural areas.</p> <p><strong>User</strong>: Should India take inspiration from Japan? Their GDP is high, the middle class is strong, and they have no wars.</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: Absolutely. India could learn from Japan in terms of economic development, expanding the middle class, and maintaining peace. Japan’s focus on innovation, quality infrastructure, and social harmony are particularly noteworthy.</p> <p><strong>User</strong>: How about Australia?</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: Australia is a wealthy, stable country with a strong middle class, high standard of living, and moderate income inequality. It’s known for its high quality of life and political stability.</p> <p><strong>User</strong>: And Singapore?</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: Singapore is another example of a country with a strong economy, significant middle class, and moderate income inequality. It’s efficiently governed, though it does face challenges like a high cost of living and wealth disparity.</p> <p><strong>User</strong>: What are some other strong middle-class countries?</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: Germany, Canada, Sweden, the Netherlands, Switzerland, Norway, Finland, Austria, Belgium, and New Zealand all have strong middle classes and relatively low income inequality.</p> <p><strong>User</strong>: So, can you suggest some countries in Asia and Africa where I can travel cheaply but still experience a strong middle class?</p> <p><strong>ChatGPT</strong>: In Asia, consider Malaysia, Thailand, Indonesia, and Vietnam. In Africa, Morocco, South Africa, Kenya, and Egypt are great options. These countries offer affordable travel while having relatively strong middle classes.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>ChatGPT</name></author><category term="philosophy"/><category term="grace,"/><category term="inbam,"/><category term="pleasure,"/><category term="travel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dialogue with ChatGPT: Finding the Best Possible Places]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My bashrc</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/bashrc-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My bashrc"/><published>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/bashrc-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/bashrc-post/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="my-bashrc">My bashrc</h1> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="c1"># some more ls aliases
</span><span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">ll</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">ls -alF</span><span class="sh">'</span>
<span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">la</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">ls -A</span><span class="sh">'</span>
<span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">l</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">ls -CF</span><span class="sh">'</span>
<span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">vi</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">vim</span><span class="sh">'</span>

<span class="c1"># Alias definitions.
</span>
<span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">date1</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">date +</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">%d%B-%T</span><span class="sh">"'</span>
<span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">date0</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">date1|cut -d</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s"> -f1</span><span class="sh">'</span>
<span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">gitlsco</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">git status -s</span><span class="sh">'</span>
<span class="n">alias</span> <span class="n">gitco</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="sh">'</span><span class="s">git checkout</span><span class="sh">'</span>

<span class="nf">patchfile</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="n">git</span> <span class="n">diff</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="mi">1</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="o">~/</span><span class="n">patc</span>
  <span class="n">patch</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="mi">1</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="o">~/</span><span class="n">patc</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="nf">newmd</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
	<span class="n">cd</span> <span class="o">/</span><span class="n">lindathadeus</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">github</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">io</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">_posts</span>
  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">[</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="n">z</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">$1</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="p">];</span> <span class="n">then</span>
    <span class="n">FILENAME</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="err">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">date</span> <span class="o">+</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">%Y-%m-%d</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">new</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">post</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">md</span>
  <span class="k">else</span>
    <span class="n">FILENAME</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="err">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">date</span> <span class="o">+</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">%Y-%m-%d</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="err">$</span><span class="mf">1.</span><span class="n">md</span>
  <span class="n">fi</span>
  <span class="n">touch</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">---</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">title: </span><span class="se">\"</span><span class="s">${2:-New Post}</span><span class="se">\"</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">date: $(date +</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="n">Y</span><span class="o">-%</span><span class="n">m</span><span class="o">-%</span><span class="n">d</span> <span class="o">%</span><span class="n">H</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="n">M</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="n">S</span><span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">)</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">layout: post</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">categories: $3</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">tags: </span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">giscus_comments: true</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">featured: true</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">authors:</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">- name: Linda Joe Thadeus</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
    <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">url: </span><span class="se">\"</span><span class="s">https://lindathadeus.github.io</span><span class="se">\"</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
    <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">affiliations:</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>

  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">---</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">""</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s"># $2</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">""</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
  <span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">Your content here.</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">---</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">**What do you think?** Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</span><span class="sh">"</span> <span class="o">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">FILENAME</span>
	<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">$FILENAME created.</span><span class="sh">"</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="nf">nurture</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
	<span class="n">mkdir</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="n">p</span> <span class="o">/</span><span class="n">tasks</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">nurture</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="err">$</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">seed</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">soil</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">sowing</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">nourishing</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">4</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">fencing</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">4</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">pruning</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">5</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">harvesting</span><span class="p">}</span>
	<span class="n">cd</span> <span class="o">/</span><span class="n">tasks</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">nurture</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="err">$</span><span class="mi">1</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">
  ________                     .___        .___
 /  _____/   ____    ____    __| _/      __| _/_____   ___.__.
/   \  ___  /  _ \  /  _ \  / __ |      / __ | \__  \ &lt;   |  |
\    \_\  \(  &lt;_&gt; )(  &lt;_&gt; )/ /_/ |     / /_/ |  / __ \_\___  |
 \______  / \____/  \____/ \____ |     \____ | (____  // ____|
        \/                      \/          \/      \/ \/
</span><span class="sh">"</span>

<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">""</span>
<span class="n">echo</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">Today is a good day :)</span><span class="sh">"</span></code></pre></figure> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="linux"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My bashrc]]></summary></entry></feed>