<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-08-23T12:26:36+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Linda Joe Thadeus</title><subtitle>A personal website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Next Jobs</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-thoughts-on-next-jobs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next Jobs"/><published>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-thoughts-on-next-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-thoughts-on-next-jobs/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone, This is a post about my thoughts on the set of jobs that will be present after the genesis of the AI era.</p> <p>The introduction of AI has shown the world that the average knowledge work does not have to be too costly, much like when the Industrial Machines showed the world that the average hand-made product does not have to be too costly.</p> <p>Let us look at it deeper, what constitutes an average work? IMHO, whichever doesn’t require deep thinking constitutes an average work. In other words, whichever can be regurgitated using patterns from existing knowledge base, can be put inside the “AVERAGE BOX”.</p> <p>But does it mean every knowledge job out there will be made by AI? NO!, what I mean is whichever is not too costly for the customer and even cheaper than the man’s pay, will be taken over by AI. Because, AI is fast and scalablle unlike human beings.</p> <p>So, who are under risk? The highly paid average knowledge workers.</p> <p>So, who are safe? The lowly paid knowledge workers, The knowledge workers of unexplored knowledge (Ph.D folks, Niche specialist, Emerging Technology Knowledge Workers)</p> <p>What do you think? Mail me your comments.</p> <p>Cya!</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="distill"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="engineering"/><category term="jobs"/><category term="knowledge"/><category term="thoughts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="images"/><category term="links"/><category term="math"/><category term="code"/><category term="blockquotes"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My thoughts on next set of Knowledge Jobs]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Future of Jobs in the AI Era: Who’s Safe, Who’s at Risk?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/new-jobs-with-ai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Jobs in the AI Era: Who’s Safe, Who’s at Risk?"/><published>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/new-jobs-with-ai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/new-jobs-with-ai/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p> <p>This is a post about my thoughts on the set of jobs that will be present after the genesis of the AI era.</p> <p>The introduction of AI has shown the world that average knowledge work does not have to be too costly, much like when industrial machines showed the world that the average hand-made product does not have to be too costly.</p> <p><strong>But what constitutes average work?</strong></p> <p>In my humble opinion, whichever doesn’t require deep thinking constitutes average work. In other words, whichever can be regurgitated using patterns from an existing knowledge base can be put inside the “AVERAGE BOX.”</p> <p>But does it mean every knowledge job out there will be made by AI? <strong>NO!</strong> What I mean is whichever is not too costly for the customer and even cheaper than the man’s pay will be taken over by AI because AI is fast and scalable unlike human beings.</p> <p><strong>So, who is under risk?</strong> The highly paid average knowledge workers.</p> <p><strong>So, who is safe?</strong> The lowly paid knowledge workers, the knowledge workers of unexplored knowledge (Ph.D. folks, niche specialists, emerging technology knowledge workers).</p> <hr/> <h3 id="ais-response">AI’s response:</h3> <p>Your insights form a solid foundation for understanding the evolving job landscape in the AI era. Let’s explore a few additional dimensions to enrich the conversation.</p> <h4 id="clarifying-average-work"><strong>Clarifying ‘Average Work’</strong></h4> <p>You’ve defined “average work” as tasks that don’t require deep thinking and can be replicated through patterns. This is an excellent way to frame the discussion. To make it more relatable, consider providing examples: routine data analysis, content generation based on templates, or handling straightforward customer service queries are all tasks that AI can perform efficiently.</p> <h4 id="job-security-beyond-low-pay"><strong>Job Security Beyond Low Pay</strong></h4> <p>While it’s true that lower-paid knowledge workers might not be the first to be replaced by AI, there’s more to job security than pay. Adaptability, continuous learning, and the ability to collaborate with AI are becoming increasingly crucial. Workers who can integrate AI into their workflow, regardless of their pay scale, will likely be more secure in the long run.</p> <h4 id="niche-and-emerging-technologies-safe-havens"><strong>Niche and Emerging Technologies: Safe Havens?</strong></h4> <p>You’ve rightly pointed out that knowledge workers in unexplored or niche fields are safer. However, it’s essential to emphasize that these workers must remain vigilant by continually updating their skills. Emerging technologies offer opportunities for growth, requiring human ingenuity to develop and refine. Staying ahead of the AI curve involves seeking out new knowledge and expertise.</p> <h4 id="the-role-of-creativity-and-human-touch"><strong>The Role of Creativity and Human Touch</strong></h4> <p>AI excels at pattern recognition and large-scale data processing, but there are areas where human creativity, emotional intelligence, and nuanced decision-making are irreplaceable. These uniquely human traits will continue to play a critical role in the workforce. Emphasizing this can add depth to your argument about the future of work.</p> <h4 id="a-call-to-action"><strong>A Call to Action</strong></h4> <p>To make this discussion more actionable, I encourage readers to assess their careers and identify areas where they can upskill or pivot towards more AI-resistant roles. Whether it’s by embracing creativity, honing expertise in niche fields, or learning how to collaborate with AI, there are steps everyone can take to ensure they remain valuable in the AI era.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>What do you think?</strong> Let me know your thoughts in the comments below. Together, we can navigate this evolving landscape and find our place in the future of work.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="AI"/><category term="Job Market"/><category term="AI"/><category term="future of work"/><category term="job security"/><category term="emerging technologies"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi Everyone,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding Two Siblings</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/not-pretty-behaviour/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding Two Siblings"/><published>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/not-pretty-behaviour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/not-pretty-behaviour/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi folks, Today we are going to understand 2 different personality styles, a Narcissist and an Avoidant.</p> <p>Narcissist is a person who intensely needs admiration. Avoidant is a person who intensely needs independence.</p> <h4 id="narcissists-and-their-need-for-admiration"><strong>Narcissists and Their Need for Admiration</strong></h4> <p>Narcissists are often characterized by their intense need for admiration. This need isn’t just a desire but a deep-seated requirement that fuels their self-esteem and sense of worth. Narcissists thrive on validation from others, using it as a way to reinforce their self-image and maintain their perceived superiority.</p> <p>However, this constant need for admiration often comes at the expense of genuine, unconditional love. Narcissists may find themselves in relationships where they are admired but not truly loved for who they are. This superficial connection can lead to feelings of emptiness and dissatisfaction, as the external validation they crave never fully satisfies the deeper emotional needs that unconditional love would provide.</p> <p>And, Narcissists often employ not pretty tactics like manipulation, gas-lighting to get what they want, even at the expense of others in a grand way because of their grandiosity needs from the others.</p> <h4 id="avoidants-and-their-need-for-respect"><strong>Avoidants and Their Need for Respect</strong></h4> <p>Avoidants, on the other hand, are driven by a strong need for respect—specifically, respect for their boundaries and autonomy. They value their independence and often keep others at a distance to protect themselves from vulnerability and emotional pain. While this approach helps avoidants feel safe and in control, it also means they may miss out on the deeper emotional connections that come with unconditional love.</p> <p>Unlike narcissists, avoidants don’t necessarily need to be admired or praised; what they truly want is for their space and need for independence to be respected. This focus on maintaining distance can create a barrier to experiencing the kind of deep, unconditional love that requires emotional closeness and vulnerability. As a result, avoidants may suffer from feelings of loneliness or a sense of missing out on the full richness of relationships.</p> <p>And, Avoidants too employ not pretty tactics like manipulation, gas-lighting to get what they want, even at the expense of others but very subtly because of their freewill, empathetic needs from the others and maybe that is why avoidants are not hated as much as their narcissist sibling.</p> <h4 id="the-common-ground-conditional-needs"><strong>The Common Ground: Conditional Needs</strong></h4> <p>Both narcissists and avoidants suffer because their primary needs—admiration for narcissists and respect for avoidants—often overshadow their need for unconditional love. For narcissists, the endless pursuit of admiration doesn’t fulfill their deeper emotional needs, leaving them in a perpetual state of dissatisfaction. For avoidants, the safety and security of maintaining distance can lead to a lack of deep, fulfilling connections, resulting in loneliness and emotional isolation.</p> <h4 id="when-can-they-both-be-good-people-for-others"><strong>When can they both be good people for others?</strong></h4> <p>Contrary to popular belief they both can be good to others, but terms and conditions applied. Basically, as long as the grandiosity needs are fulfilled, a narcissist is the best parent, partner. Similarly, An avoidant is the best parent and partner, when their freewill needs are fulfilled.</p> <p>Ultimately, by acknowledging and addressing these underlying needs, both narcissists and avoidants can work towards healthier, more fulfilling relationships that provide not just what they want, but what they truly need.</p>]]></content><author><name>Linda Joe Thadeus</name></author><category term="psychology"/><category term="relationships"/><category term="grace"/><category term="Narcissism"/><category term="Avoidant Attachment"/><category term="Relationships"/><category term="Psychology"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi folks, Today we are going to understand 2 different personality styles, a Narcissist and an Avoidant.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to setup github pages?</title><link href="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to setup github pages?"/><published>2024-08-19T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-19T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lindathadeus.github.io/blog/2024/my-first-post/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="how-to-setup-github-pages">How to setup github pages?</h1> <p>This is my first post on my new Jekyll-powered website.</p> <p>In this post, we will look at the steps to create a website using github pages. The github pages has its limitations too. It can only serve static sites. But, for a portfolio website, this is more than enough. Blogging can also be done using the github’s comments feature.</p> <p>Github uses jekyll, which is a static site generator for this.</p> <p>So, let us get into it</p> <p>Steps</p> <ol> <li>Create a repository like <username>.github.io and make the default branch as main</username></li> <li>install jekyll, blunder</li> <li>Follow below cli</li> </ol> <figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="n">git</span> <span class="n">clone</span> <span class="n">git</span><span class="nd">@github.com</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="n">lindathadeus</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">lindathadeus</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">github</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">io</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">git</span>
<span class="n">sudo</span> <span class="n">apt</span> <span class="n">install</span> <span class="n">jekyll</span>

<span class="n">cd</span> <span class="n">name</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">github</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">io</span>
<span class="n">jekyll</span> <span class="n">new</span> <span class="p">.</span>

<span class="n">git</span> <span class="n">add</span> <span class="p">.</span>
<span class="n">git</span> <span class="n">commit</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="n">m</span> <span class="sh">"</span><span class="s">hello github pages</span><span class="sh">"</span>
<span class="n">git</span> <span class="n">push</span> <span class="n">origin</span> <span class="n">main</span></code></pre></figure> <p>And, then, goto https://lindathadeus.github.io, thats it!</p> <p>Hope, you could set it up too :) Stay tuned for more!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="linux"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to setup github pages?]]></summary></entry></feed>